It was the heist before Christmas.
The Grinch is a family, comedy, animation film directed by Yarrow Cheney.
The Grinch hatches a scheme to ruin Christmas when the residents
of Whoville plan their annual holiday celebration.
Grinch (voice), played by Benedict Cumberbatch.
Donna Lou Who (voice), played by Rashida Jones.
Bricklebaum (voice), played by Kenan Thompson.
Cindy Lou Who (voice), played by Cameron Seely.
Mayor McGerkle (voice), played by Angela Lansbury.
Narrator (voice), played by Pharrell Williams.
Seuss' The Grinch (or simply The Grinch) is a 2018 American animated
Christmas comedy film based on How the Grinch Stole Christmas!
Produced by Illumination, it was directed by Scott Mosier and Yarrow
Cheney and written by Michael LeSieur and Tommy Swerdlow.
Narrated by Pharrell Williams, the film stars Benedict Cumberbatch as the Grinch, with
Rashida Jones, Kenan Thompson, and Angela Lansbury in supporting roles.
The plot follows the Grinch, who plans to stop Whoville's Christmas celebration by
stealing all the town's decorations and gifts, with his pet dog Max.
The film is the third screen adaptation of the book, following the
1966 television special and the 2000 live-action film.
It was announced in 2013, and by 2016, Cumberbatch was cast, and
Cheney and Peter Candeland were set to direct.
In 2018, Mosier took over Candeland's position as co-director.
Danny Elfman composed the score, with a song written
and performed by Tyler, the Creator.
The Grinch was released in the United States on November 9, 2018, by Universal.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $540 million, becoming the
highest-grossing Christmas film in history, as well as the highest-grossing Dr.
Seuss film adaptation.
The film explores themes of holiday, surrealism,
remake, based on children's book, christmas.
The tone is lighthearted and mind_bending.